Guide to the Mario Cardullo Papers, 1953-2013 MS2387
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mario Cardullo Papers
1953-2013
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Cardullo, M. W. (Mario W.), 1935-
MS2387
26 Linear Feet
This collection contains documents, records, photographs and other materials related to Mario Cardullo. The material dates from 1955 to 2013. Dr. Cardullo was a writer and inventor, most known for creating modern radio-frequency identification (RFID) technology. In addition, he held numerous other patents.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Series 2, Subseries 10 contains confidential correspondence regarding patent information. Special Collections will review materials in this subseries before researchers can access this subseries. Please contact Special Collections for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mario Cardullo, 2019 (2019.037). An addition was donated by Mario Cardullo in 2021 (2021.021).
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Mario William Cardullo (b. May 16, 1935) is a prolific inventor and writer, most known for creating the modern RFID. He received his BMA and MME at the Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute (now the New York University Tandon School of Engineering), his MEA at the George Washington University School of Engineering and Applied Science, and his PhD in Information Technology from George Mason University. He worked as a System Engineer for Bellcomm, Inc., contributing to the Apollo Program. Cardullo later worked for Communications Satellite Corp, where he worked on maritime communications satellites in 1966. He developed the RDIF-TAG in 1969. He holds numerous patents for his inventions, and has served as a college professor and adjunct. Cardullo has published over 200 works, including 2 textbooks, and several papers and articles. Among other accolades, Cardullo was selected for the Engineering Hall of Fame at The George Washington University in 2007, was nominated to the US Patent Office Hall of Fame in 2010 and has received the Bronze Medal for Outstanding Service from the US Department of Energy.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains documents, records, photographs, slides, negatives, transparencies, newspaper clippings, journals, publications, reports, correspondence, memos, personal files and receipts from Mario Cardullo. The material dates from 1955 to 2013.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into 3 series: Education; Professional; and Personal and Office Records. The Professional series is divided into 12 sub-series, with each series representing a company Cardullo worked for, as well as patents, publications and miscellaneous files.
Engineering; Inventions; Science; Technology; Information technology; Radio frequency identification systems; Cardullo, M. W. (Mario W.), 1935-
- Education, 1953-2013; 1953-1959; 2012-2013; MS2387 Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  The material in this series includes documents, records, correspondence, publications, and copies of degrees. They range in date from 1953-2013, with the bulk of the records from 1953-1959 and 2012-2013. The files represent Mario Cardullo's undergraduate and graduate education at the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn (now known as the Tandon School of Engineering at New York University), and his PhD work at George Mason University.
  Arrangement
  The folders are arranged chronologically.
  - Transcript - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1953-1956; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Record Books, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Class Cards, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - An Analysis of Two Dimensional Fuel Slurry Element, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1956 September 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Rocket Society, Student Chapter, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bachelor Degree, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1957 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Graduate Degree Correspondence, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Graduate School Transcript, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - A Study of Liquid Jet Instability, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1958 January 05 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Equations of State and Fluid Flow, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1959 May 04 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Master's Degree, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1959 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - GMU Doctoral Forms, MS2387 Series 1 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - PHD Disseration Forms, 2012-2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - New Global Reserve and its Management, Directed Reading Course IT [1/2], 2012; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Dissertation Oral Exam/Personal Notes [1/2], 2013 January 23; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Dissertation Oral Exam/Personal Notes [2/2], 2013 January 23; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Dissertation Research Papers [1/2], 2012-2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Dissertation Research Papers [2/2], 2012-2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - SDR Valuation [1/3], 2012; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - SDR Valuation [2/3], 2012; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - SDR Valuation [3/3], 2012; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Proposal for Dissertation, 2012; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Presentation + Notes [1/2], 2012-2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Presentation + Notes [2/2], 2012-2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - SDR Charts, 2012-2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Dissertation Proposal, 2012 April; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Dissertation Data, 2012-2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Dissertation Notes, 2012-2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Backround Material, 2012-2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Dissertation Writing, 2012-2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Dissertation- Development of Information and Knowledge Architectures and an Associated Framework and Methodology for System Managment of A Global Reserve Currency, 2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Dissertation [1/2], 2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Dissertation [2/2], 2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Dissertation Defence [1/3], 2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Dissertation Defence [2/3], 2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Dissertation Defence [3/3], 2013; MS2387 Series 1 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- Professional, 1957 June - 1988 August 26; 1957-1994; 2007-2012; MS2387 Series 2
  This series contains documents, reports, publications, drawings, memos, correspondence, receipts, photos, negatives, transparencies, slides, and newspaper clippings that relate to Mario Cardullos professional life. The material ranges from 1957 - 2002.
  The series is divided into 12 sub-series. Series 1-10 arranged in chronological order, Series 11 and 12 arranged in order received by doner. Each sub-series relates to a company that Cardullo worked at, as well as patents, publications and other micellnous files relating to Cardullo's professional career. Within each sub-series, folders are arranged chronologically. Folders that are undated are arranged alphabetically, and placed after the chronologically ordered folders.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Seires 2, Subseries 10 contains confidential corespondence regarding patent information. Special Collections will review materials in this subseries before researchers can access this subseries. Please contact Special Collections for more information.
  - Liquid Rocket Propulsion Laboratory, Picatinny Arsenal, Dover, New Jersey, 1957-1961; MS2387 Series 2 Subseries 1
    This sub-series contains documents, records, correspondence, reports, publications, notes, and photographs. The material ranges from 1957-1961. It relates to Mario Cardullo's work as a project engineer at the Liquid Rocket Propulsion Laboratory, Picatinny Arsenal in Dover, New Jersey. Cardullo worked here from October 1957 until November 1961. He designed rocket engines, conducted tests and formulated requirements for Navy and Army programs and managed research and development.
    The folders are arranged chronologically and folders that are undated are arranged alphabetically, and placed after the chronologically ordered folders
    - Bourdon Tube Pressure Gages, 1957 November 21 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Record of Invention, Airfoil Type Injector, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Record of Invention, Recirculation Injector Venturi, Jet Pump Type, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Ultrasonics and its Uses, 1958 February 03 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Design of Insulated Propellant Tanks, 1958 November (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Record of Invention, Under Water Ramjet Propulsion System, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Vibration Test, 1959 March (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Talk on Units, 1959 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Record of Invention, Airfoil Type Injector, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Influence Coefficients for Real Gases, 1960 February 22 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Real Gases, 1960 May (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Variable Thrust Rocket Engines, 1960 July 18-19 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Journal of the Aero Space Sciences, 1960 July (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Journal of the Aero Space Sciences, 1960 October (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Effects of Simulation and Scale-up on Performance of Rocket Nozzle Materials, 1961 May (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - First U.S. Manned Suborbital Space Flight, 1961 June 06 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Controlled Thrust Rocket Engine, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Controlled Thrust, Inc, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Misc. Drawings, Notes, Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - NARTS, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Notes on Liquid Metal Heat Transfer, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Picatinny Arsenal Photos, circa 1957-1961 (Box 3, Folders 1-6)
    - Rocket Theory and Safe Rocket Experiments, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Study of Evaporation Rates and Temperature Variations in Water, Diesel, Oil and High Test Gasoline, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Honeywell Aeronautical Division, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1960 December 06 - 1963 January 16; MS2387 Series 2 Subseries 2
    This sub-series contains documents, records, correspondence, reports, publications, and notes. The material ranges from 1961-1963. This sub-series relates to Mario Cardullo's work as a senior development engineer at Honeywell Aeronautical Division in Minneapolis, Minnesota. Cardullo worked here from November 1961-March 1963. He was responsible for the design, development, and served as a market liaison for reaction control propulsion systems.
    The folders are arranged chronologically and folders that are undated are arranged alphabetically, and placed after the chronologically ordered folders.
    - Background in Reaction Controls, 1960 December 06 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Reaction Control Propulsion System for LEM, 1961 August 09 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Hypergolic Bipropellant Reaction Control Development, 1961 September 21 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Generalized Heat Transfer Analysis for Rocket Engines, 1961-1964 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Propellant Tank and Metal Expulsion Bladder Assembly, 1962 February 28 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Attitude Control and Stabilization System for an Orbiting Vehicle, 1962 May 07 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Positive Flow Meter, 1962 May 29 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Scout Velocity Control Thrust Package, 1962 June 11 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Facilities for Reaction Control, 1962 July 30 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Reaction Control Engine for the Saturn Space Vehicle, 1962 October 3 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Detonation Reaction Control, 1962 October 29 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Honeywell Pushes Vehicle Controls Effort, 1962 Nov 5 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - American Rocket Society, 1962 November 13-18 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Honeywell Reveals New Space Vehicle Rockets, 1962 November 15 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Metal Expulsion Diaphram Development, 1962 December 02 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Generalized Heat Transfer Analysis for Rocket Engines, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Subliming Solid Microrocket, 1963 January 16 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Chemical Rocket Engines for Attitude Control of Space Vehicles, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Misc Drawings, Memos, Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Military Products Group Sales School, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Reaction Control Systems, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Bellcomm Inc., Washington, DC, 1962 October - 1965 December 29; MS2387 Series 2 Subseries 3
    This sub-series contains documents, reports, and publications. The material ranges from 1962-1965. It relates to Mario Cardullo's work as a member of the technical staff at Belcomm, Inc. in Washington, D.C. Cardullo worked here from March 1963 until November 1965. He was assigned to the Apollo program, performed various system planning studies and reviewed top-level NASA programs, schedules, and costs.
    - Closed Loop Heat Transfer Test Apparatus, 1962 October (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Employment Letter and Personnel Security Questionnaire, 1963 February 25 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Flight Test Plan Review, 1963 December 26 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Bellcomm Reports, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Detonation Reaction Control, 1964 March (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Crushable Nozzle for LEM Descent Engine, 1964 May 13 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - LEM Landing Gear, 1964 May 14 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Lunar Touchdown Abort, 1965 June 29 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Design Program for Rocket Nozzles, 1965 September 01 (Box 6, Folder 9, Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Bellcomm Gift to Mario, 1965 November 10 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Launch Vehicle Strategies, 1965 December 29 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Appollo Proulision Systems, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Game Theory applied to Flight Readiness Tests, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Communications Satellite Corporation, Washington, DC, 1961 - 1973 March 04; MS2387 Series 2 Subseries 4
    This sub-series contains documents, reports, publications, memos, and correspondence. The material ranges from 1961-1973. It relates to Mario Cardullo's work as a planning officer and member of the technical staff at Communications Satellite Corporation in Washington, D.C. Cardullo worked here from November 1965-January 1970. He prepared and evaluated corporate goals, plans, and alternatives. He also developed system plans for utilization of satellites for domestica nad other applications, and coordinated these activities with the company, governmental and international agencies.
    - The Economic Potential of Communication Satellites, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Joint Cost and Price Discrimination, 1963 July (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Technical Memoranda, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Maritime Satellite Service: Applications for Safety, 1967 June (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Statistical Variations in Performance of Rocket Engines, 1967 August (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - A Scenario for Organizing, 1967 October (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Policy Planning Report 68-1, 1968 May 09 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Maritime Satellite Service, 1968 August 15 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Memo: Initial Traffic Forecast Model, 1969 January 14 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Mobile Communications Via Satellite, 1969 September (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - FCC Plans to Review Policy on Earth Station Ownership, 1969 December 08 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Record Book, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - The Automated Broadcast Market, 1972 December 11 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Naval Satellites Set Newspaper Clipping, 1973 March 04 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Appendix A: Business and Regulatory Background of US Telecommunications, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - COMSAT Misc. Chart, undated (Flat box 23, Folder 1)
    - COMSAT Reports, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Early Bird/Intelesat, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Misc Papers, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Recommended Areas for Research and Development, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Federal Energy Administration, Washington, D.C., 1976 December - 1986 April 28; MS2387 Series 2 Subseries 5
    This sub-series contains reports, publications, correspondence, drawings, transparencies, and slides. The material ranges from 1976-1986. This sub-series relates to Mario Cardullo's work at the Federal Energy Administration in Washington, D.C.
    - Northern Tier Supply Curtailment, 1976 January (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Petroleum Supply Alternatives for the Northern Tier States, 1976 November (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Petroleum Supply Alternatives for the Northern Tier States Through 1980, 1976 December (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Petroleum Supply Alternatives for the Northern Tier States Through 1980, 1977 June (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Report on Throughput and Capacity of the Mid-Continent Petroleum Pipeline Systems, 1977 June (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Projected Crude Oil and Petroleum Shortages in the Northern Tier of the United States, 1977 September 29-30 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Northern Route Study Vol I, 1978 February 02 - August 04 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - The Disposition of Alaskan North Slope Crude Oil, 1978 April 10 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Northern Tier Study Briefing Material, 1978 August 15 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Impact of Mexican Crude Oil Exportation, 1978 August 31 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Mexico's Oil and Gas Policy: An Analysis, 1978 December 06 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Northern Route Study Vol II, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Draft Report, Petroleum Supply Alternatives for the Northern Tier and Inland States through the year 2000 Executive Summary. Vol 1, 1979 February 21 (Box 10, Folders 5-6)
    - Draft Report, Petroleum Supply Alternatives for the Northern Tier and Inland States through the year 2000 Appendices Vol 2, 1979 February 21 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Office of Energy Transportation Policy Vol III, 1979 August 03 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Petroleum Supply Alternatives for the Northern Tier and Inland States Through the Year 2000, 1979 October 31 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - National Energy Transportation Study, 1980 July (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Energy Supply Transportation, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Misc. Correspondence, Reports, Drawings, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Report on Potential for Cost Reductions in Inland Transportation of US Coal Exports, 1983 August (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Effect of US Coal Exports on Domestic Economic Growth and on US National Security, 1984 January (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Recent Developments in US Coal Exporting Capability, 1984 February (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - FE Energy Supply Transportation and Coal Export Activities, 1984 March (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - US Coal Exports: The Italian Example, 1986 April 28 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - US Coal Exports: The Italian Example, 1986 April 28 (Flat box 22, Folder 1)
    - Western Coal Transportation Administration, 1986 September 22 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Record Book, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - International Trade Administration, US Department of Commerce, Washington, DC, 1990-2005; MS2387 Series 2 Subseries 6
    This sub-series contains reports, publications, correspondence, office records, and receipts. The material ranges from 1990-2005. This sub-series relates to Mario Cardullo's work at the International Trade Administration of the US Department of Commerce in Washington, D.C.
    - The Commercial Prospects for Amorphous Metal Transformers, 1990 June (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - The Commercial Prospects for Amorphous Metal Transformers, 1990 August (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Non-Reimbursable Loans of Personnel Services, 1991 January 23 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Long Range Strategic Planning Support for the Office of Propulsion Vehicles, 1992 January 31 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Performance Appraisal, 2000 July 12 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - DOC- Calling Card, 2000 February 05 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Employee Express, 2002 February 14 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Fax INMARSAT, 2002 October 03 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - FEHB, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Travel, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Expense Vouchers, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Security Initiative Update, 2003 January (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Smart and Secure Trade Lanes, 2003 February 26 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - From RFID to Smart Dust "The Expanding Market for Wireless Sensor Technologies, 2004 April (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - International Travel Order, 2005 August 09 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Detail and Transfer of Federal Employees to International Organizations, 2005 August 15 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Home Leave, 2005 August 15 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - International Travel Order, 2005 September 07 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Justification of Detail to UNECE, 2005 November (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - DOC - Visa, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Genesis of the Versatile RFID Tag, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Information Sources and Timing, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Life Insurance, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Misc, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Position Descriptions, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Strategic Plans, Goals, and Measures Assessment, Performance Measure Summary, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Communications Services Corporation, Telserv Rockville, Maryland, 1968-1970; MS2387 Series 2 Subseries 7
    This sub-series contains documents, reports, publications, memos, correspondence, newspaper clippings, transparencies, and slides. The material ranges from 1968 - 1970. This sub-series relates to Mario Cardullo's work at Communications Services Corporation and Telsev, Inc. in Rockville, Maryland Cardullo worked here from January 1970- August 1971. Here, Cardullo was the president and founder of these companies and established an integrated system for the acquisition and processing of medical data from remote locations as a service industry.
    - Iowa South East Evaluation Report, 1968 October (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Utilization of Human Resources and Facilities, Diocese of Davenport, Iowa, 1969 January (Box 14, Folders 2-3)
    - The Catholic Messenger, 1969 November 06 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Comserv Slides, 1969 (Box 21)
    - Iowa South East Evaluation Interpretive Analysis, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Iowa South East Evaluation Supplementary Data, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Iowa South East Evaluation Slides, 1969 (Flat box 22, Folders 2-4)
    - Proposed Evaluation Archdiocese of Washington, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Environmental Forecasting Conference, 1970 January 18-23 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Reference Manual - Electrocardiogram, 1970 July 01 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Information Procedure and Price Schedule, 1970 September 01 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - BioServ Model, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Capabilities and Resources, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Computer Interpretation of Electrocardiogram, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Comserv Financials, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Corporate Business Plan, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Corporate Business Plan w/ Appendices, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Dental Health, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Misc. Binder, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Yankee Noodle Dandy, 1983-1988; MS2387 Series 2 Subseries 8
    This sub-series relates to Mario Cardullo's work at Yankee Noodle Dandy. It contains documents, reports, publications, correspondence, photographs, and negatives. The material ranges from 1983-1988. Cardullo founded this pasta restaurant.
    - Unidentified Restaurant, 1983 November (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Pasta Shop, Italy, 1983 December (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Pasta Bella I San Francisco, 1984 July (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Pasta I and II, 1984 July (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Prints from Babette Augustin, 1985 February 15 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Washington Post Reviews, 1985 June 24 (Box 17, Folder 6)